it's time to start trading from the
right order block after this video
you'll be able to point out valid order
blocks you'll be able to refine those
you are not meant to be trading from and
stick to the valid ones so I'm going to
stud the rules you need to see present
before pointing out your POI that is
your UT block so make sure you watch
till the very end I've gotten the
question a lot on how to map out the
auto block out of your origin so in
today's video it's going to be stress
forward so watch to the very end guys
let's go to the chat
we're going to start with the meaning of
order block order blocks refer to
specific price areas where large Market
participants such as institutional
Traders have previously placed
significant buy or sell orders now let
me use an illustration to explain this
particular definition because it's just
a very straightforward and simple
definition so remember our strategy if
we get a break of structure like this to
the upside
we are waiting for prize to come and tap
into the origin that caused the break of
structure then for price to keep pushing
to the upside because it has created a
break of structure here so we expecting
price to retrace back into the origin
that caused the break of structure to
dish out a buy now these impulsive
movements that caused this break of
structure this break of structure that
we have here
this impulsive movement that caused this
break of
structure is actually the
buy that has been placed here by
institutional Traders so the idea behind
the order block is that
since um an order has been placed
here we're expecting markets to come and
retrace into this particular level where
order has been placed which is what we
call our order block we're expecting
Market to come and tap into this
particular level and clear out other you
know unmitigated orders here so once
price stops in there we're expecting it
to like finish up the unmitigated orders
here and push again to the upside so
that is the meaning of other block and
the idea behind the other block with
trade so let me clear this we're going
to look at the measor rules from the
second book
which is here the measor rules for order
block so for you to get a valid order
block these are the major rules you need
to see present number one it must break
a structure or cause a change of
character so markets may be moving and
maybe you've pointed out an other block
but make sure that the impulsive
movement that you've noticed actually
clear the structure if you don't
understand the meaning of break of
structure you can check out my video on
break of structure to understand that so
make sure that any other block you
mapping out has broken a structure or
has caused a change of character number
two it must be unmitigated now what I
mean by all mitigated is make sure that
your UT block price or Market has not
tapped into it because once Market has
tapped into an order block it is no
longer valid it will become liquidity
zone so so make sure that the auto block
has not been tapped into that is it must
be unmitigated the next one is imbalance
must be present now following the entry
strategies we use you know with SMC um
strategy inbalance is actually one of
the entry um strategy but for me I don't
take my entries from inbalance that is
fvg I take my entries from other block
and inbalance will be present to give
more validity to my aut block so
imbalance is more like one of the
confluences I need to see present for me
to consider my aut block valid so
inbalance must be present the aut block
you are mapping out it must be the last
Candlestick reaction in An Origin let me
use an illustration to explain that so
you noticed a range you know whenever
Market is ranging that simply means both
the buyers and the sellers they
indecisive so whenever Market is ranging
once you get an impulsive movement it
either to the upside or to the downside
here we're going to use to the upside so
inside this consolidation now you know
price kept on you know they were
fighting both the Bulls and the Bears
until the buyers you know cleared to the
upside that's winning the fight so all
the consolidation inside here is what I
call origin generally but if you want to
map out your other block you need to
look for the last Candlestick inside the
consolidation that is inside the origin
you look for the last candles reaction
it can be bullish Candlestick it can be
bearish Candlestick so just look for the
last Candlestick before the movement
that caused the other block that is what
you map out from the opening to the
closing and extend it because that will
be your trap when we go to the Chart you
understand clearly so this is just an
illustration so we're still on number
four it must be the last Candlestick
reaction in An Origin then liquidity
sweep is a plus now what I mean by
liquidity sweep you may notice other
blogs like this um let me use an
illustration again you may notice other
blocks with weak rejection that is
Market cleared liquidity before it
started pushing to the upside so it's
kind of a plus to our strategy let's say
you notice other block Candlestick like
this and you notice that price cleared
liquidity before it started pushing so
this week projection is more like a
liquidity sweep it must not always be
present that's why I said liquidity
sweep is a plus so once you notice that
your other block cleared liquidity your
other block candle cleared liquidity
before the main impulsive
movement the main impulsive movements
that cleared a structure it's also you
know valid it adds more validity to the
other block so once you map it out you
just specially wait for price to come
into that particular Orion so that we
rejection that is it's more like a plus
to the rules so if you notice it you
know it adds it makes other block more
valid so I've also stated where it works
like when it works and number one here
it works more when Market has a
Direction so if you have finished
reading the market structure you should
also understand how to read Market
structure if you want to do well with
this particular strategy I also have a
video on that teaching you how to read
Market structure so if you read the
market structure and you notice that
there's no direction in the market you
need to stay away because you may not
get the setup you are looking for but
once you read the Market structure and
you notice that there's a direction and
the direction is either to the upside or
to the downside then your other blocks
can work well we also have number two it
also works more when the market is
volatile so it's more like same with
when the market has a Direction so
volatility in the market simply means
how high the momentum is so when the
market is giving out you know good
movement and it's not just slow you know
like during asan section Market is
always slow but during London and New
York section you will get the movement
the momentum you're looking for so it
works more when the market is volatile
and you need to make sure you are
sticking to the recent aut blocks that's
what I mean by recent obies so don't go
and map out you know unrealistic aut
block and expect Market to get there you
may be missing out on your entries so
make sure you work with recent other
blocks when we go to the chat I will
clarify that then allow the price or the
market to clear liquidity if you're also
confused on what liquidity means you can
also check my video on liquidity to
understand it so allow the price to
clear liquidity let's say we have a
break of structure and you've noticed
the market is kind of ranging around
here this being your origin where you're
waiting for price to get to and you
notice that market is playing around
here don't be tempted to get in wait for
price to clear this liquidity before
tapping in and then it will move to your
direction because if the liquidity the
market needs to sweep to tap into your
origin is not present then that simply
means your origin or your other block
will turn to the liquidity so we're
going to open the chart now I'm going to
show you guys some of the trads I've
taken how all these rules repres because
if I don't see them present I'm not
taking my trades that is how I do my
piece of mind keeping everything simple
you don't need to rush so I'm going to
show you guys examples of some of the
TRS I've taken and then after this video
I'm going to drop a link where if you do
your own analyses map out your own other
block you can go ahead and send you know
to show me if you're correct that would
be commended but if you're not you'll be
corrected so let's go to the Chart so
this is a sale I took on BTC USD so
noticing the trend um from my entry time
frame after pointing out that um BTC was
bearish so I came to my entry time frame
which is 15 minutes to look out for you
know ways to join the trend that is the
bearish trend so pointing out a break of
structure here to the downside another
break of structure here to the downside
then this being the most recent break of
structure when I was looking at the
market here the most recent break of
structure now remember I talked about
origin I stated that the consolidation
that will be happening before an
impulsive movement now this impulsive
movement that cleared the structure that
is actually the order that has been
placed now this consolidation is
actually when both the buyers and the
sellers they were more like in siing so
after the consolidation the sellers you
know cleared everywhere that simply
means the sellers you know actually won
the fight so these impossible simply
means that an order has been placed here
which is causing this massive sell off
so what I did from the consolidation I
looked out for the last take note guys
the last Candlestick which is this
bearish Candlestick here and I mapped it
out you know measuring the height of the
Candlestick that is from the opening to
the closing and I extended it as the
Trap so as an order has been placed here
triggering this impulsive movement to
the downside the reason for this
particular um order block I've mapped
out is for Market to be traced back into
that origin and then finish up the
others here finish up the unmitigated
ERS so looking at it from the origin you
pick the last
Candlestick the last Candlestick
reaction remember I stated it can be
bullish it can be bearish but just make
sure it is the last candles reaction you
measure that and then you map it out now
if you check from the rules I stated you
can see we have our fvg present which I
mapped out here that is it fvg so
imbalance must be you know present for
your other block will be valid you know
most people may ask if the imbalance is
not present is it a good trade it can be
a good trade but learn to stick to your
A+ setup because B if all my confidences
are not intact I'm not taking the trade
so it's it must be an A+ setup for me
before I click the buy button or the
sell button so there's no need to rush
in taking premature entries wait for
everything to be present then you take
your trades so looking at it my
imbalance present and you can see the
liquidity price cleared before tapping
into my origin so these dollar and you
seeing here suppl liquidity so PR you
can see when price got here it was you
know trying to like trick me into taking
TR from there but I waited patiently for
Market to get into my origin and you can
see immediately it cleared the liquidity
tapped in with dropped to the downside
and this Tre dished out 316 Pips on BTC
very clean make sure you follow the
trend and once you get a break of
structure remember the rules the other
block must cost a break of structure
which is here and then when you map it
out you look out for inbalance liquidity
that price will sweep and it must be the
last Candlestick that uh that's the last
Candlestick reaction before the
impulsive movement let me also show you
guys another example this is another
beautiful entry that is a sale on GBP
JPY this particular Trad dished out a
lot of you know funds for me now the
market is bearish you can see break of
structure to the downside break of
structure to the downside and then when
I was looking at the market this was
actually the most recent break of
structure you can see that clearly and
everything inside here they are all
consolidation so all of them is what I
call origin generally but now if I want
to set my trap I'll look out for the
last Candlestick now let me zoom in so
that you will see this is the last
Candlestick now this is a bullish
Candlestick that's why I
said um when you're mapping out your aut
block whether it is a bearish or a
bullish Candlestick just make sure it is
the last Candlestick reaction before the
imposs movement now you can see the
massive sell off here so after this
consolidation a sell order was placed
here by you know institutional Traders
Market Movers which triggered this
impulsive movements that cleared
uh this structure to the downside so all
I did was to map out the last
Candlestick reaction you know
highlighting it from the opening to the
closing and then extending it now you
can see price rallied back tapped into
the origin and you know dished out
massive movement for me so in here I was
just risking 38 Pips to catch 169 Pips
so it's a trade of 1 is to 4 is to
reward ratio now checking for other
rules is my imbalance presence of course
this is it fvg where is the liquidity
price cleared you know before tapping
into my origin this is the liquidity
present and you can see immediately
price cleared my liquidity tapped in and
it pushed to the downside have it in
mind that if you have one of them
missing that tread is not an A+ setup
and if your liquidity is not there have
it in mind that your origin or the other
block or your POI that you mapped out
may be the liquidity and price may end
up stopping you out before moving to
your direction so so just make sure
everything you are doing on the chart is
clean Precision entries make sure that
all your confes are intact let me also
show you guys another example now look
at this beautiful Buy on XA USD that is
gold so you can see Market clear
structure to the upside here and if you
check price came back into the origin
that caused the breakout structure you
can see it a little tapping inbalance
present and the rest but this is the one
I want to show you guys because this is
the one that dig up funds for me I
didn't this one I missed this so but
this is me just showing you guys how to
map out the other block you can see
inside here the consolidation what did I
do you highlight the last you know
Candlestick before the impulsive
movement now after price tapped into
this particular origin it dished out
another Breck of structure to the upside
which we can see here clearly so inside
the movements the origin everything
inside
here yeah all the origin before the
impulsive movement so inside there all I
just need to look out for carefully is
the last Candlestick that caused um the
impulsive movement that is the last
Candlestick reaction and I will
highlight it that is my trap that is how
I set my trap very simple so once you
highlight that you now start looking out
for other things that need to be present
before you know um priz will tap into
your origin that is giving the other
block more validity now if you check we
have our fvg present and we have the
liquidity so you can see after price
cleared the liquidity it tapped in and
immediately price pushed to a direction
dishing outa number of Pips so this is
just how simple I keep it mapping out
your order block inside the
consolidation look out for the last
Candlestick guys last Candlestick that's
all and make sure that there is a break
of structure then after the break of
structure look out for other conferences
FG liquidity that price will sweep to
tap in that's how you keep it simple and
you take your trads in well in a well
refined way guys so I will allow you
guys to go ahead and you know go and do
the practice on your own chat cuz like I
stated this video is meant to be very
simple and straight to the point so
there is no need you know beating around
the bush so make sure you practice
because practicing will make you more
perfect if you just watch and go and see
down then that simply means you're not
ready to pack out the funds out of the
market so now that you've seen how I you
know refin my entries taking my trads
from the last Candlestick before the
impuls movement the last Candlestick
reaction that's the Precision entry so
stop taking your um trades wrongly or
mapping out your Origins wrongly so go
and practice on your own chat a link
will be in the description you can
message me with your setup and I will
see whether you mapping it out Wily so
guys thanks for watching and expect more
videos